Guide to the William L. Amoss papers 0251.UA
Special Collections and University Archives
- Publications, 1886-1936; 6; 4.50 Linear Feet
  - African-American Education and Labor -- Calhoun Colored School, of Calhoun, Lowndes County, Alabama., 1899-1903; 6.2.2 (Box 2, Folder 2.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor -- Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute, 1900-1913; 6.2.3 (Box 2, Folder 3.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor -- "The Negro Farmer", 1903; 6.2.4 (Box 2, Folder 4.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor -- Southern Education Board, May 1902, December 1902; 6.2.5 (Box 2, Folder 5.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor -- Southern Education (Journal), March 1903-November 1903; 6.3.1 (Box 3, Folder 1.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor --Southern Industrial Classes, 1904, 1906,1913; 6.3.2 (Box 3, Folder 2.0)
  - African-American Education and Labor -- Southern Workman, The (Journal), 1901, 1903, 1904; 6.3.3 (Box 3, Folder 3.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- The Atlantic Monthly: The Problems of Rural New England, May 1897; 6.4.1 (Box 4, Folder 1.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: Respiration Experiments with Sweet Potatoes, December 1915; 6.4.2 (Box 4, Folder 2.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: The Disease of Potatoes Known as "Leak", July 1916; 6.4.3 (Box 4, Folder 3.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: A New Disease of Wheat, July 1917; 6.4.4 (Box 4, Folder 4.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: A Needle Blight of Douglas Fir, July 1917; 6.4.5 (Box 4, Folder 5.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: A Nursery Blight of Cedars, September 1917; 6.4.6 (Box 4, Folder 6.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: Some Changes in Florida Grapefruit in Storage, December 1920; 6.4.7 (Box 4, Folder 7.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: After-Ripening and Germination of Apple Seeds, January 1923; 6.4.8 (Box 4, Folder 8.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of Agricultural Research: The Effect of Outside Rows on the Yields of Plots of Kafir and Milo at Hays, Kansas, May 1926; 6.4.9 (Box 4, Folder 9.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences: The Formation of Leaf mold, February 1914; 6.4.10 (Box 4, Folder 10.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- New Zealand Journal of Science and Technology: The Boron Status of Fruit and Leaves in Relation to "Internal Cork" of Apples in the Nelson District, 1935; 6.4.11 (Box 4, Folder 11.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- New Zealand Journal of Science and Technology: Soil Phosphate Studies, 1935; 6.4.12 (Box 4, Folder 12.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- New Zealand Journal of Science and Technology: Control of Forest Insect Pests, 1935; 6.4.13 (Box 4, Folder 13.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- New Zealand Journal of Science and Technology: Further Note on Pear Midge Parasite, 1935; 6.4.14 (Box 4, Folder 14.0)
  - Excerpted Articles -- Popular Science Monthly: The Illinois System of Permanent Fertility, January 1914; 6.4.15 (Box 4, Folder 15.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes -- The American Association of Farmers' Institute Managers, 1897-1898; 6.4.16 (Box 4, Folder 16.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes -- American Association of Farmers' Institute Workers, 1901, 1907, 1909, 1911; 6.4.17 (Box 4, Folder 17.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes -- History and Form of Organization, 1902, 1906, 1907; 6.4.18 (Box 4, Folder 18.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes -- Indiana, 1907; 6.4.19 (Box 4, Folder 19.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes -- Pennsylvania, 1909, 1911; 6.4.20 (Box 4, Folder 20.0)
  - Farmers' Institutes -- Wisconsin, March 1908; 6.4.21 (Box 4, Folder 21.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- 999 Queries with Answers from Landreths' Book of Inquiries upon Agricultural and Horticultural Subjects, 1895; 6.4.22 (Box 4, Folder 22.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Boston Society of Natural History Guides for Science Teaching: Common Hydroids, Corals and Echinoderms, 1888; 6.4.23 (Box 4, Folder 23.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Clover Farming, 1898; 6.5.1 (Box 5, Folder 1.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Concrete Construction about the Home and on the Farm, 1905; 6.5.2 (Box 5, Folder 2.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- The Cow Pea, Undated; 6.5.3 (Box 5, Folder 3.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- The Dorset Ewe in America [The Winter Lamb], 1901; 6.5.4 (Box 5, Folder 4.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- The Farm Cement News, 1910; 6.5.5 (Box 5, Folder 5.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Foot Notes on Kafir Corn, Sorghum and Stock Peas, Undated; 6.5.6 (Box 5, Folder 6.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Fundamental Principles of Plant Breeding, 1902; 6.5.7 (Box 5, Folder 7.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- National War Garden Commission, 1918-1919; 6.5.8 (Box 5, Folder 8.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Sewage Disposal for Country Homes, 1914; 6.5.9 (Box 5, Folder 9.0)
  - Farming and Gardening Manuals -- Strawberry Culture, 1904; 6.5.10 (Box 5, Folder 10.0)
  - Homemakers' Booklets -- American School of Home Economics, December 1908; 6.5.11 (Box 5, Folder 11.0)
  - Homemakers' Booklets -- Cornell Reading Course for Farmers' Wives, November 1903; 6.5.12 (Box 5, Folder 12.0)
  - Homemakers' Booklets -- Illinois Association of Domestic Science, 1905; 6.5.13 (Box 5, Folder 13.0)
  - Homemakers' Booklets -- Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Associations, May 1908; 6.5.14 (Box 5, Folder 14.0)
  - Homemakers' Booklets -- Nutrition for the Family, June 1923; 6.5.15 (Box 5, Folder 15.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- [Australia] Queensland Department of Agriculture, 1890; 6.5.16 (Box 5, Folder 16.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- Bermuda Department of Agriculture, 1927; 6.5.17 (Box 5, Folder 17.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- [Canada] Ontario Department of Agriculture Women's Institutes, 1908 and undated; 6.5.18 (Box 5, Folder 18.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- [India] Forest Zoology, 1909, 1910; 6.5.19; Oversize (Box 5, Folder 19.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- Irish Agricultural Organisation Society, Limited, 1901, 1911; 6.5.20; Includes oversize (Box 5, Folder 20.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- [Mexico], Undated; 6.5.21 (Box 5, Folder 21.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- New South Wales, 1928; 6.5.22 (Box 5, Folder 22.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- North Wales Agricultural Organisation Society, 1910; 6.5.23; Includes oversize (Box 5, Folder 23.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- Porto Rico [Puerto Rico], February 1914; 6.5.24 (Box 5, Folder 24.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- Scotland, 1905; 6.5.25 (Box 5, Folder 25.0)
  - International Agricultural Publications -- West Midland Farmers' Association, Ltd., 1911; 6.5.26 (Box 5, Folder 26.0)
  - Journals -- Journal of Agricultural Research, October 1917 - September 1926; 6.6.1 (Box 6, Folder 1.0)
  - Journals -- Men's Welfare, July 1904, April 1905; 6.6.2 (Box 6, Folder 2.0)
  - Journals -- The Nature-Study Review, March 1908; 6.6.3 (Box 6, Folder 3.0)
  - Journals -- The Pedagogical Seminary, 1898, 1899; 6.6.4 (Box 6, Folder 4.0)
  - Journals -- The Pedagogical Seminary, 1901, 1902, 1905, 1915; 6.7.1 (Box 7, Folder 1.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- Arrowfield Nurseries: Pecan Trees for Northern Planting, Undated; 6.7.2 (Box 7, Folder 2.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- Evergreens offered by Fairfax Farms Nursery, Undated; 6.7.3 (Box 7, Folder 3.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- International Irrigation Committee, November 1906; 6.7.4 (Box 7, Folder 4.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- Live Stock Contagious Disease Laws of Maryland, 1886; 6.7.5 (Box 7, Folder 5.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- The Millers' Review, 1909; 6.7.6; Oversize (Box 7, Folder 6.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- National Research Council Organization and Members, 1931-1932; 6.7.7 (Box 7, Folder 7.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- Right Relationship League Cooperative Farming Pamphlets, 1910 and undated; 6.7.8 (Box 7, Folder 8.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- Rindge Park Playground, Cambridge, Massachusetts, Annual Report, 1905; 6.7.9 (Box 7, Folder 9.0)
  - Pamphlets and Advertisements -- Snohomish County Horticultural Association Year Book, 1906; 6.7.10 (Box 7, Folder 10.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- U. S. Department of Agriculture, 1914, 1926; 6.8.1 (Box 8, Folder 1.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- University of Arizona College of Agriculture, July 1924; 6.8.2 (Box 8, Folder 2.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- California Fruit Growers Exchange, 1914; 6.8.3 (Box 8, Folder 3.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- Iowa State College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, 1918; 6.8.4 (Box 8, Folder 4.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- Illinois Corn Growers Association, 1902; 6.8.5 (Box 8, Folder 5.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- University of Illinois, 1900-1901; 1907-1920; 6.8.6 (Box 8, Folder 6.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- University of Kentucky College of Agriculture, January 1923; 6.8.7 (Box 8, Folder 7.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- Michigan State Agricultural College, 1910, 1916, 1918; 6.8.8 (Box 8, Folder 8.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- Michigan Weather Service, July - November 1895; 6.8.9 (Box 8, Folder 9.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- University of Minnesota Agricultural Extension Division, April 1918-March 1923; 6.8.10 (Box 8, Folder 10.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- University of Missouri College of Agriculture, 1914; 6.8.11 (Box 8, Folder 11.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- New Jersey Agricultural College Experiment Station, 1892-1912; 6.8.12 (Box 8, Folder 12.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- New Jersey State Board of Agriculture, 1904, 1909, 1913; 6.8.13 (Box 8, Folder 13.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- [New York] Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, April 1901-June 1922; 6.8.14 (Box 8, Folder 14.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- New York Agricultural Experiment Station, 1898-1916; 6.9.1 (Box 9, Folder 1.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- Ohio Agricultural Experiment Station, 1909-1917; 6.9.2 (Box 9, Folder 2.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- Oregon Agricultural College Extension Service, November 1923; 6.9.3 (Box 9, Folder 3.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- Pennsylvania State College Agricultural Experiment Station, March 1912, August 1915; 6.9.4 (Box 9, Folder 4.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- Pennsylvania State Weather Service, January 1888; 6.9.5 (Box 9, Folder 5.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- State Horticultural Association of Pennsylvania, March 1926; 6.9.6 (Box 9, Folder 6.0)
  - State Agricultural Publications -- Texas Agricultural Experiment Station, 1912-1916; 6.9.7 (Box 9, Folder 7.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- Vermont Department of Agriculture, 1912, 1914; 6.9.8 (Box 9, Folder 8.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- Wisconsin Geological and Natural History Survey, 1903; 6.9.9; Includes oversize (Box 9, Folder 9.0)
  - State Agricultural Reports -- Wisconsin [promotional brochure], 1904; 6.9.10 (Box 9, Folder 10.0)
- Photographs, 1896-1914; 7; 4.00 Linear Feet 4.00 linear feet, 212 photo negatives, and 253 photographs; 253 photographs; 212 photographic_negatives; 4.00 Linear Feet
  The Photograph series includes 164 albumen or black-and-white prints, 89 cyanotypes, 15 5x7 glass plate negatives, and 197 large format negatives. Prints include depictions of Green Ridge Orchard; farm scenes; livestock; groups of men and groups of men and women; a beach scene; a hunting scene; men outside a pub with a sign reading "Ice Cold Beer" (ca. 1900); campus greenhouses; botany experiments; students in the entomology and botany departments; male students fencing and lifting weights; a baseball game; and scenes from the Farmer's Institute.
  Negatives include depictions of farms, sheep, and a greenhouse; produce, including celery, tobacco, flowers, and watermelon varieties; beekeeping hives; and images from the 1904 St. Louis World's Fair (Louisiana Purchase Exposition) including buildings, state agricultural exhibits (Nebraska, Illinois, Colorado, California, Washington, Arkansas), corn, watermelons, wheat, apples, and the Canada and Mexico exhibits.
  This series has been transferred to the Photograph collection. Photographs that were previously removed to the Biographical Photographs - Print File collection have been reintegrated into the series. Photographs that were previously removed to the Subject Photographs - Print File collection have been returned to the Amoss collection, but remain unprocessed and separate from the rest of the series.
- Memorabilia, 1905 and undated; 8; 6 items
  The Memorabilia series includes one ribbon and four badges dating from Amoss's tenure as director of the Farmers' Institutes and one envelope commemorating his role as a Maryland Commissioner to the 1904 Louisiana Purchase Exposition, at which he was in charge of the Agricultural exhibit.
  - Memorabilia, circa 1905 and undated; 8.1.1 (Box 1, Folder 1.0)
    - Ribbon; Maryland Agricultural College. "Director Institutes.", ca. 1905; 8.1.1.48 (Box 1, Item 48)
    - Badge; 1 1/4"x5 3/4" white with blue lettering. Maryland Agriculture College, Trustee, President, Director Institutes, Director Station, undated; 8.1.1.374 (Box 1, Item 374)
    - Badge; 1 1/4"x5 3/4" white with blue lettering. Maryland Agriculture College, Trustee, President, Director Institutes, Director Station, undated; 8.1.1.375 (Box 1, Item 375)
    - Badge; 1 1/4"x5 3/4" white with blue lettering. Maryland Agriculture College, Trustee, President, Director Institutes, Director Station, undated; 8.1.1.376 (Box 1, Item 376)
    - Badge; 1 1/4"x5 3/4" white with blue lettering. Maryland Agriculture College, Trustee, President, Director Institutes, Director Station, undated; 8.1.1.377 (Box 1, Item 377)
    - Envelope; 2 3/4"x8 3/4" white(?). Maryland Commissioners to the Louisiana Purchase Exposition, St. Louis, MO, William L. Amoss, in charge, Agricultural exhibit, undated; 8.1.1.378 (Box 1, Item 378)